<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Healthcare on Sparkle Russell-Puleri</title>
    <link>https://sparalic.github.io/tags/healthcare/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Healthcare on Sparkle Russell-Puleri</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 11:58:08 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sparalic.github.io/tags/healthcare/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting 30 Readmission risk for ICU patients:  unsupervised clustering of patient sub-populations for multitask learning using electronic health records</title>
      <link>https://sparalic.github.io/post/readmission-risk-final/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 11:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sparalic.github.io/post/readmission-risk-final/</guid>
      <description>by: Sparkle Russell-Puleri
Problem Readmission whether planned or unplanned costs the U.S healthcare system billions of dollars annually. This, among other things, is of great importance to healthcare systems, since about one-third of readmissions are preventable, providing a huge opportunity for hospital systems to improve their quality of care 1. This compounded with the fact that hospitals are also penalized with up to 3% lower reimbursements from the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services(CMS) for increased readmission rates, as a part of the 2012 affordable care act passed by the Obama admistration 2, creates a huge oppotunity for the use of data to build algorithms that are capable of prediciting which patients are likely to be readmitted if discharged early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting future medical diagnoses with RNNs using Fast AI API from scratch</title>
      <link>https://sparalic.github.io/post/predicting-future-medical-diagnoses-with-rnns-using-fast-ai-api-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sparalic.github.io/post/predicting-future-medical-diagnoses-with-rnns-using-fast-ai-api-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>by: Sparkle Russell-Puleri
In the first part one of this tutorial we created a rough template of the Doctor AI: Predicting Clinical Events via Recurrent Neural Networks paper(2016) by Edward Choi et.al. In this tutorial we took it a step further using the Fast.ai buttom up approach. This code is fully functional and details on how the data was processed can be accessed in part one.
Load Data
About the data set</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Electronic Health Records to predict future diagnosis codes with Gated Recurrent Units</title>
      <link>https://sparalic.github.io/post/using-electronic-health-records-to-predict-future-diagnosis-codes-with-gated-recurrent-units/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sparalic.github.io/post/using-electronic-health-records-to-predict-future-diagnosis-codes-with-gated-recurrent-units/</guid>
      <description>Background: Detailed review of Doctor AI: Predicting Clinical Events via Recurrent Neural Nets (Choi et.al 2016)
by: Sparkle Russell-Puleri and Dorian Puleri
Electronic medical records( EMRs), which is sometimes interchangeably called Electronic health records(EHRs) are primarily used to electronically-store patient health data digitally. While the use of these systems seem commonplace today, most notably due to the passing of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act in 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>